MyMasterCook is a useful application that may help its users find numerous recipes, based on ingredients, cuisines and even meals that one can search in the “search” tab on the bottom of the application view. Some other tabs that can be found are the “home” tab, “favourites” tab and “settings” tab. In the “home” tab, the user can find recipes related to the time of day. As describes its name, the “favourites” tab is where a user’s favourited recipes can be found. This tab is only accessible while user is logged in. If not logged in, the customer can still navigate in the application as a guest, however, as mentioned previously, the “favourites” tab is inaccessible.

To find a recipe, the user can type in any ingredient in the "search" tab or select a meal or cuisine. To enter an ingredient, type it in the "enter ingredient" area and press the "+" sign next to it, push the "search" button and find recipes including all entered ingredients. The user can see what they entered in order above the search bar. To clear a previously entered ingredient, the user can swipe left on the ingredient and the "delete" button will appear. To clear all entered ingredients, press the "clear" button. Once the user has selected a recipe, written instructions as well as a video description will be available to use.

In the "settings" tab the customer can see "log in" button (if navigating as a guest) or "log out" button, the application "about" and "privacy policy" and the "delete account" button.

